A December Bride is a romance, tv movie film directed by David Winning.
Aspiring interior designer Layla is dreading the Christmastime
wedding of her cousin who’s marrying Layla’s ex-fiancé.
Although Seth is the one responsible for introducing the bride and groom, she
begrudgingly accepts his offer to be her date as she’s out of options.
Seth gets carried away at the reception and announces they’re
engaged, forcing a mortified Layla to keep up the pretense.
Seth, played by Daniel Lissing.
Layla, played by Jessica Lowndes.
Darcy Sterling, played by April Telek.
Aunt Lorraine, played by Karen Kruper.
Jessica Evans, played by Pauline Egan.
Beckett O'Reilly, played by Casey Manderson.
Bride of Frankenstein is a 1935 American horror film, and the first
sequel to Universal Pictures' 1931 film Frankenstein.
As with the first film, Bride was directed by James Whale, starring
Boris Karloff as the Monster and Colin Clive as Dr.
Frankenstein.
Additionally, it features Elsa Lanchester in the dual role of Mary Shelley and the bride, Ernest
Thesiger as Doctor Septimus Pretorius, and Oliver Peters Heggie as the blind hermit.
Taking place immediately after the events of the earlier film, it is rooted in a subplot of the
original Mary Shelley novel, Frankenstein; or, The Modern Prometheus (1818).
Bride follows a chastened Henry Frankenstein as he attempts to abandon his plans to
create life, only to be tempted and finally blackmailed by his old mentor Dr.
Pretorius, along with threats from the Monster, into
constructing a bride for the Monster.
Preparation to film a sequel to Frankenstein began shortly after its
premiere, but script problems delayed the project.
Principal photography on Bride of Frankenstein finally commenced in January 1935, with creative
personnel from the original returning both in front of and behind the camera.
The film was released to critical and popular acclaim, although it encountered
difficulties with some state and national censorship boards.
Since its release Bride of Frankenstein's reputation has grown, and it is now
frequently considered one of the greatest sequels ever made.
Many critics consider it to be an improvement on the
original, and have hailed it as Whale's masterpiece.
In 1998, it was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the National Film
Registry, having been deemed "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of holiday, romcom, christmas, pretend relationship.
The tone is emotional and intense.